Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
5583/3
Kheel Center
86.3 linear ft.
Records, publications.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into four sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-44
Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Boxes 82-87 have not been inventoried at this time.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pullman Company.; Pullman-Standard Car Manufacturing Company.; Purdue University.; Quaker Oats Company.; Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Division.; Railway Express Agency.; Ralston Purina Company.; Republic Aviation Corporation.; Republic Steel Corporation.; Research Council for Economic Security.; Research Institute of America, inc.; Resistoflex Corporation.; Revere Copper and Brass Incorporated.; Reynolds Metals Company.; Reynolds Metals Company. Consumer Products Division.; R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company.; Rheem Manufacturing Company.; Ritter-Conley Manufacturing.; Ritter Company.; Ritter-Pfaudler Corporation.; Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway Company.; Rockbestos Product Corporation.; Royal McBee Corporation.; Rubber Manufacturers Association (U.S.); Rutgers University. Institute of Management and Labor Relations.; Rutgers University.; St. Regis Paper Company.; Samsonite Corporation.; San Diego Gas and Electric Company.; San Francisco Employers Council.; Sangamo Electric Company.; Sargent and Company (New Haven, Conn.); Scott Paper Company.; Sealed Power Corporation.; Sears, Roebuck and Company.; Shell Oil Company.; Sinclair Oil Corporation.; SKF Industries, inc.; Society for Advancement of Management.; Society of Federal Labor Relations Professionals (U.S.); Socony Mobil Oil Company.; Socony-Vacuum Oil Company.; Solar Aircraft Company.; Southern California Edison Company.; Southern New England Telephone Company.; Southern Pacific Company.; Southern Regional Council.; Spencer Kellogg and Sons, Inc.; Sperry Gyroscope Company, inc.; Sperry Rand Corporation.; Standard Oil Company.; Standard Oil Company of California.; Standard Oil Company (Indiana); Standard Oil Company of New Jersey; Standard Oil Company (Ohio); Standard Oil Development Company.; State Farm Insurance Companies.; State Farm Mutual Automobile Insurance Company.; State Mutual Life Assurance Company (Worcester, Mass.); John B. Stetson Hat Company.; Stromberg-Carlson Telephone Manufacturing Co.; Studebaker Corporation.610:; Studebaker-Packard Corporation.; Sun Oil Company.; Supermarket Institute.; Swift & Company (Chicago, IL); Sylvania Electric Products, Inc.; Sylvania Electronics Systems.; Taylor Instrument Companies.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; Texaco, inc.; Texas Company.; Texas Instruments Incorporated.; Thatcher Glass Manufacturing Company.; Thompson Products, inc.; Thompson Ramo Wooldridge, inc.; Time, inc.; Time Share Corporation.; Timken Company.; Todd Shipyards Corporation.; Toledo Labor-Management-Citizens Committee.; Transportation Association of America.; Travelers Insurance Companies.; TRW Inc.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; Twentieth Century Fund.; Twin City Rapid Transit Company.; Union Bag-Camp Paper Corporation.; Union Carbide Corporation.; Union Electric Company of Missouri.; Union Labor Life Insurance Company.; Union Oil Company of California.; Union Pacific Railroad Company.; Uniroyal, inc.; United Aircraft Corporation.; United Airlines.; United Brands Company.; United Gas Corporation.; United Shoe Machinery Corporation.; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.; United States. Bureau of Employment Security.; United States. Bureau of Federal Credit Unions.; United States. Bureau of Labor-Management Reports.; United States. Bureau of Labor Standards.; United States Civil Service Commission.; United States. Civil Aeronautics Administration; United States. Congress.; Job Corps (U.S.); U.S. Congress of Mayors.; United States. Department of Agriculture.; United States. Department of Commerce.; United States. Department of Defense.; United States. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.; United States. Department of Labor.; United States. Department of State.; United States. Department of the Air Force.; United States. Department of the Army.; United States. Department of the Interior.; United States. Department of the Navy.; United States. Department of the Treasury.; United States. Federal Trade Commission.; United States.General Accounting Office.; United States. General Services Administration.; United States. Internal Revenue Service.; United States. Interstate Commerce Commission.; Library of Congress; United States. National Labor Board.; United States.Office of Economic Opportunity.; United States. Railroad Retirement Board.; United States Rubber Company.; United States. Securities and Exchange Commission.; United States. Small Business Administration.; United States. Social Security Administration.; United States. Social Security Board.; United States Steel Corporation.; United States.Veterans Administration.; Volunteers in Service to America.; University of San Francisco.; Upjohn Company.; W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research.; Upjohn Institute for Community Research.; Workmen's Compensation Board of Vancouver (B.C.); Victor Adding Machine Co.; University of Washington.; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.); Wayne State University.; Weirton Steel Corporation.; Welch's; University of the West Indies; West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company.; Western Electric Company.; Western Michigan University; Western Railways.; Western Union Telegraph Company.; Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company.; Weston Electrical Company.; Weyerhaeuser Timber Company.; George Wiedemann Brewing Company.; H.W. Wilson Company; Wisconsin Electric Power Company; University of Wisconsin.; Wyandotte Chemicals Corporation.; Xerox Corporation.; Yale Towne Manufacturing Company; Yale University; Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company.; Zenith Radio Corporation.
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings -- Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives --Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce --Marketing -- Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Telecommunication.; Transportation equipment industry.; Trucking industry.; Trucks -- Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records.; Publications
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this Collection:
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3 5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 2: Boxes 23-44
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3, Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Boxes 82-87 have not been inventoried at this point.
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 67, Folder: 1 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Accounting Department Personnel Requirements and Training, 1965; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Author: A.H. Bosse
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Administration and Economics Volume XII, Number 1, 1965
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Lubricants Test Illustrations, 1953; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Voluntary Evening Classes For United States Steel Employees, Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Notes: Advanced Technical Study Program
  - Item 4: Accounting Department Personnel Requirements and Training, Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: A Management Development Program For Engineers, 1963; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Author: C.H. Williams
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Administration and Economics Volume X, Number 28, 1963
  - Item 6: Industrial Accounting Careers in United States Steel, 1950; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Dynamic Management for Profit, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Author: A.E. McDonough and G.H. Krapf
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Management and Economics Colume VII, Number 77 -- 1960
  - Item 8: Maintenance Apprenticeship Program, Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Administration and Economics Volume VI, Number 27
  - Item 9: Training for Industrial Careers, 1952; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Author: E.E. Moore
  - Item 10: Discussion Guide: Program Introduction; Slide Script; Discussion of Examples, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Notes: Management Benefits Training Program
- Box: 67, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: A New Approach To Office Mechanization: Integrated Data Processing Through Common Language Machines, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Principles of Management: Supervisory Training Program, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    Notes: Series One
  - Item 3: Panel Discussion preliminary To 1951 National Employ The Physically Handicapped Week, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    Author: John A. Stephens
  - Item 4: Training Young Engineers, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    Author: R.O. Hawkanson
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Administration and Economics Volume VI, No. 10
  - Item 5: Some Experience with Air Pollution Abatement In the Steel Industry, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    Author: C.A. Bishop
    Notes: A Technical Paper
  - Item 6: Job Training Discussion Guide, 1951; Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
- Box: 67, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Guaranteed Annual Wage Bibliography, 1955; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Agreement Between United States Steel Corporation and the United Steelworkers of America, 1956; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Explanation of Steel Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Plan, Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Notes: With Appended Complete Text
  - Item 4: Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Plan, 1974; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Supplemental unemployment Benefit Plan, 1969; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Notes: Establised Pursuant to Agreement with United Steelworkers of America
  - Item 6: Supplemental unemployment Benefit Plan, 1962; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Savings and Vacation Plan (Revised), 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Notes: Established Pursuant to Agreement with United Steelworkers of America
  - Item 8: Management Incentive Plan, 1954; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: Wage Chronology No. 3: United States Steel Corp., Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Notes: Supplement No. 7 - 1956-57
  - Item 10: No 110: Experience with Incentive Eage Plans, 1952; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Author: T.L. Carroll
    Notes: A Technical Paper from Untied States Steel Corporation
  - Item 11: The Control and Audit of Wage Incentives, 1958; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Author: J.F. Robinson
    Notes: Technical Paper: Business Administration and Economics Volume VI, No. 8
  - Item 12: Uniform Job Classification of Wage Incentive Development, 1951; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Author: J.D. McCall
    Notes: A Technical Paper from United States Steel Corporation
  - Item 13: No. 96: Conservation of Manpower By The Use of Wage Incentives, 1952; Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Author: Myron W. Lewis
- Box: 67, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Savings Fund Plan for Salaried Employes, 1968; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: Savings and Vacation Plan For Hourly Paid Employees of United States Steel Corporation, 1969; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Savings and Vacation Plan for Salaried Employees of United States Steel Corporation, 1969; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Savings Fund Plan For Salaried Employees, 1975; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
    Notes: plan Booklet
  - Item 5: The Human Factor in Industry, 1951; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Compensation Program For Management, 1975; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Compensation Program for Non-Exempt, Salaried Employees, 1975; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Compensation Program for Non-Exempt, Salaried Employees: Plants and Mines, 1975; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: United States Steel Foundation, Inc. Annual Report for Fiscal Year Ended November 30, 1966, Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: United States Steel Foundation, Inc. Annual Report for Fiscal Year Ended November 30, 1967, Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: Job Description and Classification Manual for Hourly Rated Production, Maintenance and Non-Confidential Clerical Jobs, 1953; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 12: Savings and Vacation Plan (Revised) for Hourly Paid Employees of United States Steel Corporation, 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 13: Savings Fund Plan For Salaried Employes, 1965; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 14: Savings and Vacation Plan (Revised) For Salaried Employees of United States Steel Corporation, 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 15: Savings Fund Plan for Salaried Employes, 1963; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 16: Savings And Vacation Plan (Revised) for Hourly Paid Employees of United States Steel Corporation, 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
- Box: 67, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Statement by R. Conrad Cooper Executive Vice President--Personnel Services Untied States Steel Corporation before the Cub-Committee on Unemployment and the Impact of Automation of the House Education and Labor Committee, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Wage Chronology: United States Steel Corporation 1937-64, 1965; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Wage Chronology: United States Steel Corporation 1937-60, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Wage Chronology: United States Steel Corporation 1937-55, 1956; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: The Wage Chronology Series The United States Steel Corporation 1937-, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Notes: Series 4, No. 3
  - Item 6: Guaranteed Annual Wage Bibliography 1924-1955, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: No. 105: The Will to Work More Effectively, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Author: R. Conrad Cooper
  - Item 8: No. 110: Experience with Incentive Wage Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Author: T.L. Carrol
  - Item 9: No. 96: Conservation of Manpower By the Use of Wage Incentives, 1952; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: The Control and Audit of Wage Incentives, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: The Chairman's Letter, 1959; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Notes: The U.S. Steel Quarterly Vol. 13, No. 3
  - Item 12: Stock Option Incentive Plan of United States Steel Corporation, 1955; Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    Author: J. Carlisle MacDonald
    Notes: Additional Statement of Benjamin F. Fairless, Chairman of the Board, United States Steel Corporation, before United States Senate Committee on Banking and Currency
- Box: 67, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Management Benefits, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Explanation of Steel Supplemental Unemployment Benefit Plan, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: With Apended Complete Text
  - Item 3: Program Insurance Benefits For Employees of United States Steel Corporation and Subsidiary Companies, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Salaried Employees
  - Item 4: Savings Fund Plan For Salaried Employes, 1965; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Plan Booklet
  - Item 5: 1962 Contributory Pension Rules, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: (Part IV-A Pension Rules)
  - Item 6: United States Steel 1962 Non-Contributory Pension Rules, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Part II-D Pension Rules
  - Item 7: Program of Insurance Benefits For Employes of United States Steel Corporation And Subsidiary Companies, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Salaried Companies
  - Item 8: Program of Insurance Benefits For Employes of United States Steel Corporation And Subsidiary Companies, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Hourly Paid Employees
  - Item 9: Group Insurance Plan For Eligible Salaried Employees, 1956; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: Guidelines for Safety, 1955; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Management Improvement Series No. 3
  - Item 11: Regulations Relating to Employee Pension, Annuity, Profit-Sharing, And Stock Bonus Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Notes: Treasury Decision No. 6203
  - Item 12: Notice of Appointments, 1953; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Program of Aid to Education with Direct Grants, 1962; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: Program of Aid to Education with Direct Grants, 1966; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 15: Program of Aid to Higher Education, 1965; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 16: Program of Aid to Education, 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 17: Program of Aid to Education, 1964; Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
- Box: 67, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Dictatingis An Easier Way, 1962; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: Management Analysis Service
  - Item 2: Training for Supervisors in Employee-Management Cooperation, 1963; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Employment Benefits For Veterans Administration Employees, 1959; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Count Your Benefits, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Chapter 5: Educational Programs of Allied Medical Services, 1962; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: These Are Yours!, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: Salary; Life Insurance; Opportunity for Promotion; Cash for Ideas; Retirement Benefits; Financial Protection Against Sickness, Accident, Unemployment; Vacations and Holidays with Pay
  - Item 7: Retirement Planning Kit, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Common Sense About Managing Your Management Job, 1959; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: The Winning Letter, 1957; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: VA Pamphlet 5-20: Common Sense About Writing to People
  - Item 10: A Program for the Selection, Training and Placement of Personnel Assistants, 1962; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: GS-200-5 & 7 For Target Positions At GS-7 and 9
  - Item 11: Management Reading List, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 12: The In-Basket Exercise, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: Training Guide TG 5- 19
  - Item 13: Veterans Administration mangement Development Program, 1956; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: Questions and Answers
  - Item 14: Self-Analysis Questionnaire, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 15: Common Sense About Evaluating and Recognizing Performance, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 16: Common Sense About Supervising People, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: Key Points in Personnel Relations
  - Item 17: The 4-5 Programan Evaluation, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 18: How to Improve Your Handwriting, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    Notes: A Practical Guide to Legibility
- Box: 67, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Employee Training - for Whom and What Kind, 1960; Publication (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: The Role of Supervisor in Effective Personnel Management: A Means of Improving Quality and Reducing Costs, 1961; Publication (Box 67, Folder 8)
    Notes: Supervisory Development Conference Series